# SPENCER TRUETT

FULL-STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

## CONTACT

(615) 972-3614

▼ STRUETT.DEVELOPER@GMAIL.COM

GITHUB.COM/SPENCERTRUETT

in LINKEDIN.COM/IN/SPENCER-TRUETT/

# **PROJECTS**

#### **MEDJOURNAL**

FRONT-END CAPSTONE
HTML | CSS | JAVASCRIPT | REACT | CHART.JS

MedJournal is a mobile-focused web application designed for users to easily access and log medical details in one convenient location.

- Users record health data in forms created using React.js
- Data from the forms is dynamically populated into charts with the use of Chart.js
- Each data-point is able to be edited and deleted from an on-screen list
- Meals and Medication can be recorded using forms created using React.js
- Medications toggle between "Taken" and "Upcoming" Lists recording a timestamp
- All charts can be viewed in the "Profile View" to give an overview

Link:

https://github.com/SpencerTruett/MedJournal

# **EDUCATION**

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT CERTIFICATE
NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

STUDIED MOLECULAR BIOLOGY

LIPSCOMB UNIVERSITY | 2011 - 2014

## **PROFILE**

Born and raised in middle Tennessee, I began my college career at David Lipscomb University. After server years of soulsearching, I started teaching music to high school students locally. Ironically, it's one of those students who led me to Nashville Software School and, ultimately, my love of coding.

I decided to try out a coding "jumpstart" at NSS, and I was immediately hooked. It was then that I jumped into coding with both feet and never looked back. Coding has been a non-stop journey of wondrous new endeavors, ambitious challenges to overcome, and marvelous discoveries to uncover. I've learned that the world of coding is filled with a neverending plethora of new things to discover, which excites me to no end!

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### JUNIOR FULL-STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL | NOV 2019 - MAY 2020

INTENSIVE FULL-TIME 6 MONTH SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROGRAM LEARNING FULL-STACK TECHNOLOGIES THROUGH THE CREATION OF APPLICATIONS INDIVIDUALLY AND IN THE GROUP SETTING.

- Hands on application and experience with HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, C#/.NET
- Built browser-based, full-stack applications
- Utilized GitHub for source code version control and collaboration
- Use and creation of multiple API's using JSON Server
- Working with SCRUM methodology for team projects

# NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL PROJECTS MEDJOURNAL

- · Utilized JavaScript, HTML, CSS, & Internal Database using JSON-Server
- Record patient data in easy-to-use forms
- Display data in charts utilizing Chart.js
- full CRUD capabilities

Link: https://github.com/SpencerTruett/MedJournal

#### NUTSHELL

- Utilized JavaScript, HTML, CSS, & Internal Database using JSON-Server
- Group project building an social media like application
- Users had chatroom functionality
- Add and Remove Friends
- Post and view articles and events based on friends list
- Create a task list, which toggles between complete and to-do lists Link: <a href="https://github.com/nss-cohort-37/nutshell-conspiracy-of-lemurs">https://github.com/nss-cohort-37/nutshell-conspiracy-of-lemurs</a>

#### **BACK-END CAPSTONE**

- Ipsum Thestral dirigible plums, Viktor Krum hexed memory
- Ipsum Thestral dirigible plums, Viktor Krum hexed memory
- Ipsum Thestral dirigible plums, Viktor Krum hexed memory
- Ipsum Thestral dirigible plums, Viktor Krum hexed memory

Link: https://github.com/SpencerTruett/Capstone\_Link\_Ipsum\_Ipsum\_Ipsum

#### FREELANCE MUSICIAN/EDUCATOR

SELF-EMPLOYED | AUG 2012 - MAY 2018

- Performed vocal and instrumental percussion both locally and globally
- Instructed students in private lessons and classroom settings across Middle Tennessee
- Responsible for the coordination of parents and students for multiple school events
- Created daily lesson plans while being able to respond to an agile work environment

#### FREELANCE LEGAL COURIER

SELF-EMPLOYED | NOV 2014 - MAY 2018

- Delivered important legal documents on behalf of judges and lawyers throughout the Middle Tennessee area
- Responsible for delivering in a timely manner
- Expected to respond appropriately in a professional, legal setting